# XIAOXU ZHOU

- **♀** 2/8 Cleary Road, Panmure, Auckaland, New Zealand
- ☑ zhouxxu1985@gmail.com
- **C** 0210768411
- http://www.zhouxiaoxu.com

### **OBJECTIVE**

I'm looking for full-time work in the role of Web developer.

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Hi, this is Dan. I have 9 years work experience (4 years front-end + 4 Years Back-end). My strong capabilities with creating visually stunning responsive web pages and interfaces make me a valuable team member. I have a strong detail focus and excellent time management skills, allowing for fast completion of web site projects. I'm certain you will be impressed by the skills I can offer as a Full Stack Web Developer.

4 years+ experience in JS, HTML, CSS3

2 years+ experience in JQuery, Backbone, Nodejs, Grunt, Dojo

3 years+ experience in JAVA, Struts, Spring, Hibernate, SQL

Hands-on Reactjs experience but less than 1 year

See my web site to find more project information http://www.zhouxiaoxu.com

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# RocketShp

Auckland, New Zealand Jul 2019 - Jul 2019

#### IBM

Dalian, China Apr 2018 - May 2018

#### IBM

Dalian, China Iul 2013 - Feb 2018

### iSoftstone

Dalian, Chine Nov 2010 - Aug 2012

# Web Developer

Wordpress, Siteground, Responsive

This is my first practice in New Zealand which happened during the break of my study. I developed a responsive website for Rocketshp's client.

 As the only developer, I am responsible for almost everything, including domain/DNS configuration, environment set-up, page development, and speed optimization.

### Application Developer

Java, Spring, DB2, Jersey

IBM "荟专享" is built on Wechat Mini Program Platform. I am the only backend developer who is responsible for the Restful APIs development using Java and DB2.

- Back-end development
- DB Design
- Deployment
- Functional testing

### Web Developer

JS, Html, Css, Dojo (03/2013-2015)

JS, Html, Css, JQuery, Backbone, Grunt, Node.js, Scss (2015-2018)

IBM w3 is an internal website integrated with many features like News, Media, E-learning, Polls and so on. As one of the three main developers, I am responsible for developing redesigned visual pages, integrating different features through provided APIs and customizing search results.

- Front-end development based on sponsors' requirement
- The integration testing and issue fixing.
- Daily reporting to the manager in scrum meeting.
- The maintenance of back-end proxy server.

### Java developer

Java, Spring, Camel, Oracle

I was assigned to British Telecommunication Dalian working as a Java developer. Six months later, I was promoted to be the team leader, because of my responsible attitude towards the work.

- Functionality development based on the requirement
- Reporting team's work status to manager
- Functional testing

### Neusoft

Dalian, China Oct 2009 - Nov 2011

# Junior Java Developer

Java, Spring, Ibatis, JSP, Oracle

This is also an internal project called "Task Management System" which tracks staff daily work. It involves planning, tracking, and reporting. I wrote JSP, Servlets, and SQL to add functionality. My database skills improved a lot in this project because I wrote hundreds of SQL.

- Web page creation using Jsp.
- Designed and implemented data storage solutions
- Functional testing

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

### Eastern Institute of Technology

Auckland, New Zealand 2019

# Postgraduate Diploma in IT

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Java, Database
- Linux, Git, Grunt, Jira, Jenkins

- JQuery, BackboneJs, ReactJs, NodeJs
- · Spring, Hibernate, Jersey

# **INTERESTS**

• I enjoy the coding life.

# **REFEREES**

Referees available on request.